Sahil Thakur

Location: Dubai

Email: <u>sahil1103@gmail.com</u> Mobile: +971 52 7387770

Summary:

An enterprising professional with 14 years of global Sales expertise for multi-service Hotels and Travel Company. Exceptionally respectful & appreciative of diverse cultures and viewpoints, I am a passionate and driven Executive who has demonstrated the ability to build, lead and sustain diverse teams of professionals in a highly competitive market. Alignment, a driven team and world-class talent is what takes an organization to the next level. Maximizing Sales and improving RGI along with the Business Mix by choosing the right business segments at the right time to fill in the rooms.

Key Competencies:

Pre-Opening HotelBudgetingMarket PositioningRevenue ManagementCustomer EngagementStrategic PlanningStrategic AllianceSales & MarketingTraining & DevelopmentP&L ManagementGuest EngagementTalent Management

Experience:

August 2020 - Present: Director of Sales & Marketing

Revier – Avantime Hotels LLC – Dubai, UAE

- Heading the Commercial team in the expansion project of The Revier Hospitality Group outside
 Switzerland. Successfully assisted in planning and creating the pathway to launch the brand in Dubai as an upscale lifestyle hotel.
- Drew the brand guidelines with Marketing Manager which will be incorporated in all the upcoming Revier's.
- Assisted the Marketing Manager in heading all the marketing activities related to pre-opening and positioning of the hotel.
- Leading and supervising the sales team, oversee their day-to-day sales activities, implement action plans and accomplish goals and set targets.
- Liaising with Revenue Manager for best implementation of promotions and correct positioning of the Hotel within the Compset.
- Review direct competition and always ensure complete awareness by all sales team of competitor's activities.
- Liaising with Key partners to ensure that the Hotel is listed and sellable on their portals FlyDubai Holidays, EK Holidays etc.
- Introduced Bookers Program for local corporates to entice them to choose Revier as their preferred accommodation choice.
- Created the Sales and Marketing strategy for opening year for the sales and marketing team to focus and plan their actions in the coming months.

February 2020 – August 2020: Director of Sales

Avani Hotel Deira – Minor Hotels – Dubai, UAE

- Headhunted to re map the hotel's sales strategy and eventually the revenue stream and link all the possible segments versus the existing dependence on OTA's and Chinese Tour Groups.
- Successfully signed barter agreements for participation and marketing in German and Russian Market with Key Players in the market.
- Arranged FAM Trips from EU, India, Iraq, Iran and West Africa to promote and market the hotel within these potential markets in the area.
- Introduced Bookers Program for local corporates to entice them to choose Avani Deira as their preferred accommodation choice.
- Revived 5 lost/dormant major accounts for the hotel to get the corporate share back from the competitors.

Discussed and designed the future road map of the property with the General Manager and Director of Revenue for Sales Team to focus and plan their actions in the coming months

August 2018 – January 2020: Director of Sales & Marketing

Studio M Arabian Plaza Hotel & Hotel Apartments - Millennium Hotels & Resorts MEA – Dubai, UAE



- Part of the Pre-Opening team which successfully introduced Studio M a new brand for Millennium Hotels & Resorts.
- Successfully opened the hotel by achieving a GOP of 15.5% in the very first month.
- Awarded "Best Opening Hotel of 2018" amongst the 4 competing hotels by Millennium and Copthorne Regional Head Office.
- Awarded "Best Opening Commercial Team of 2018" amongst the 4 competing hotels by Millennium and Copthorne Regional Head Office.
- Drew the brand guidelines which will be incorporated in all the upcoming Studio M's.
- Positively introduced the concept of SMART, FUN and COOL hotel.
- Single handedly prepared the budget for Hotel as well as Hotel Apartment.
- Spear headed all the marketing activities related to pre-opening and positioning of the hotel.
- Leading and supervising the sales team, oversee their day-to-day sales activities, implement action plans and accomplish goals and set targets.
- Assisting the Sales team in visiting prospect accounts and converting them to key accounts.
- Responsible for Training and Development of the Sales and Marketing team.
- Liaising with Revenue Manager for best implementation of promotions and correct positioning of the Hotel within the Compset.
- Review direct competition and ensure complete awareness by all sales team of competitor's activities at all times.
- Consolidate month end sales report applicable information to be shared with Corporate Office, General Manager's office and Owners office.
- Formulating long / short term strategic plans to enhance profitability & revenue.

November 2015 – August 2018: Assistant Director of Sales & Marketing

Millennium Plaza Hotel – Dubai, UAE

Responsible to assist the Director of Sales & Marketing in leading and supervising the sales team, oversee the day-to-day sales activities, implement action plans and accomplish goals and set targets.



- Generate and maintain major accounts and assigned segments through various sales activities (face to face sales calls, telephone calls, entertainment, sight inspections, etc.)
- Ensure thorough and complete coverage of sales team for a comprehensive client servicing, achieving targets and maximum productivity
- Set up all sales objectives, action plans and team's targets
- Ensure that selling strategies are adhered to during negotiations and maximizes up selling opportunities of sales team
- Co-ordination and implementation of the segment sales activities and strategy with the aim of optimal room occupancy and high accommodation revenues, together with concern of the costs involved and in line with the hotel business mix.
- Development, design and calculation of attractive offers for companies with the support of the DOSM and presenting to General Manager.
- Support DOSM to ensure accurate communication of sales promotions and information that relevant people in each hotel receives copies.
- Review direct competition and align the market selling strategies accordingly with the Revenue and Sales Team.
- Consolidate month end sales report applicable information to be shared with Corporate Office, General Manager's office and Owners office.
- Develop Key Prospect Accounts to Key Accounts within a year through monitoring the share given to the hotel compared to the competition.
- Formulating long / short term strategic plans to enhance profitability & revenue.
- Formulating selling strategies during weekly revenue meeting with General Manager, Director of Sales & Marketing, Front Office Manager, Director of Revenue, F&B Manager and Director of Finance.



- Defining service standards thereby contributing towards ameliorated revenue generation across varied departments.
- Managing CVent, StarCite and Lanyon single handedly. Creating offers on CVent and submitting the proposals. Submitting RFP's on Lanyon on a regular basis.
- Planning strategy & implementing recovery tactics to ensure achievements of allotted sales & revenue targets in coordination with Revenue, MICE Sales, F&B Department & Corporate Marketing Department.
- Participating in decision-making process of the yearly budget preparation to the corporate office of M&C Hotels.
- Disciplining, scheduling, and monitoring performance in order to provide optimal guest satisfaction
- Promoting best practices to drive revenue in line with local, regional and international political & economic market

July 2011 – October 2015: Key Account Manager - Corporate

Rotana Hotels & Resorts – Dubai and Northern Emirates, UAE

Retana

- Played a key role in gaining a growth of:
 - 20% of room nights and 11% of room revenue, 2012-2013 from my portfolio
 - 10% of room nights and 15% of room revenue, 2013-2014 from my portfolio
- Took responsibility of building a sales strategy to bring back the market share of Media Rotana Hotel. Was able to implement a business strategy and got the hotel back from 0% occupancy level to 80% by capturing competition accounts and reviving the old dormant accounts of the hotel.
- Awarded as colleague of the month by AVP Sales for bringing in maximum business in a month for Rotana hotels.

March 2009 - June 2011: Agent Relations Manager - UAE

Hotels Arabia (Pronto Arabia) - UAE

- Played a key role in gaining a growth of:
 - 10% of room nights and 5% of room revenue, 2010 vs 2011 from UAE market
 - Increased room allocation for UAE hotels and was able to contract more than 50 additional hotels which were being bought via 3rd party online system.
 - Increased market share of out bound business from Local Travel agencies compared to 2010 and uplifted the revenue from UAE market by 3%.

May 2008 – Feb 2009: Assistant Sales Manager

Flora Park & Creek Hotel Apartment

• Increased share from DMC's like Gulf Ventures, Arabian Adventures, Net Tours, Desert Adventures for the Hotels.



• Introduced corporate accounts like of Redbull, Magrabi Opticals, Exterran etc to the hotel which contributed 40% of my individual sales targets

January 2007 - March 2008 - Groups & Events Coordinator with Habtoor Grand Resort & Spa, Dubai

December 2004 – December 2006 - Front Desk Officer with Hyatt Regency, New Delhi

Education:

- B.Sc. in Hotel and Hospitality Administration from Institute of Hotel Management, Chennai, India in 2004
- Higher Secondary School from S.D. Public School, Chandigarh, India in 2000

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 11th March 1982

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Punjabi **Address:** 601, H21 Building, IMPZ, Dubai, UAE